We'll always rise to the challenge!
Rise of the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles: The Movie is a animation,
action, science fiction film directed by Andy Suriano.
When a mysterious stranger arrives from the future with a dire warning, Leo is forced to rise and lead his
brothers, Raph, Donnie, and Mikey in a fight to save the world from a terrifying alien species.
Leo / Janitor Man (voice), played by Ben Schwartz.
Raph / Office Man 1 (voice), played by Omar Benson Miller.
Mikey / Foot Soldier 1 (voice), played by Brandon Mychal Smith.
Donnie / Security AI / Tank AI / Dragged Man (voice), played by Josh Brener.
Casey Jones / Foot Soldier 3 (voice), played by Haley Joel Osment.
Splinter / Additional Characters (voice), played by Eric Bauza.
Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles is a 1990 American superhero comedy film based on the
comic book characters created by Kevin Eastman and Peter Laird.
It is the first film in the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles franchise.
Directed by Steve Barron and written by Todd W.
Langen and Bobby Herbeck from a story by Herbeck, it stars Judith Hoag and Elias Koteas
with the voices of Brian Tochi, Josh Pais, Corey Feldman, and Robbie Rist.
The film follows the Turtles on a quest to save their master, Splinter, with their new
allies, April O'Neil and Casey Jones, from the Shredder and his Foot Clan.
The film adapts the early Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles comics, with several
elements taken from the animated series airing at the time.
Filming took place in 1989 in North Carolina and New York City.
Many major studios turned down distribution for the film,
worrying that it could be a box office disappointment.
New Line Cinema, at that time a small independent production
company, acquired the rights halfway through production.
The turtle costumes were developed by Jim Henson's Creature Shop, one of Jim
Henson's last projects before his death shortly after the premiere.
Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles was released theatrically in the
United States on March 30, 1990, by New Line Cinema.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $202 million on a budget of $13.5 million; it was the
highest-grossing independent film up to that time and the ninth-highest-grossing film worldwide of 1990.
It was followed by Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles II: The Secret of the
Ooze (1991) and Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles III (1993).
The film explores themes of superhero, mutant, time travel, turtle, ninja.
The tone is thought_provoking.